# Tyler Sloan, Senior Software Engineer

Clemson, South Carolina, 864-517-5609, tyler.g.sloan@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

Experience: 10+ years as Senior Software Engineer at a small web shop, an agency, and an enterprise software

startup

**Specialization:** Frontend software development with React

Languages; JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, .net, PHP

Tools: VS Code, WebStorm, GitHub, PostMan, Slack, Google Workspace

Leadership: 2 years as technical lead on agile teams, and onboarding and mentoring junior engineers

# TECHNOLOGY AND TOOLS

#### Languages:

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, PHP

#### Frameworks:

React, react-router, Remix, Vue, Sass, CSS Modules, Tailwind, Material UI

## Testing:

testing-library, Cypress, Jest

# **Dev Environment:**

VS Code, WebStorm, eslint, prettier, PostMan

#### **Development Lifecycle:**

JIRA, Github, Bitbucket, TeamCity, Laravel Forge,

## EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

May 2016 — Jan 2024

#### BoomTownROI (acquired by Inside Real Estate 2023)

Charleston / Remote

#### Senior Software Engineer - Inside Real Estate - 01/2023 - 01/2024

Technology: Vue, React, TypeScript, Tailwind, Material UI, PHP, Laravel.

- Initiated Dependencies Upgrade
  - Update repo with 325,000 lines of code and 90 dependencies from Vue 2 to Vue 3.
- Part of 4 person team integrating frontend and backend of merging real estate CRMs serving over 400,000 users, post acquisition.
- Success Assurance
  - CRM feature to show real estate agent where a lead is in the home transaction process.
- Integrated ChatGPT into existing Text, Email, and Call features,
- Enterprise Tools
  - Feature-rich application servings hundreds of in-house support engineers.
  - Refactored a TALL (Tailwind UI, Alpine js, Livewire, Laravel) stack application to a React frontend running on Vite, coupled with a Laravel API, optimizing tech stack for enhanced performance.
  - Used React and TypeScript to create UI component library on top of Material UI.

## Senior Software Engineer - BoomTown - 02/2022 - 01/2023

Technology: React, react-router, Hooks, Redux, GraphQL, testing-library, .net, c#

- · Code Quality
  - Established React development standards adopted by multiple teams, enforcing best practices and ensuring code maintainability.
- Leadership
  - Collaborated with business development teams, designers, and product departments to conceptualize, plan, and execute features.
  - Participated in hiring, onboarding, and mentoring junior developers.
  - Tech leader on agile teams, writing technical specifications, phasing out projects, writing tickets, and planning deployment strategies—seeing new features through the full software development lifecycle.
  - Provided thorough and constructive code reviews in Github.
- Wrote repo and feature wiki's to share knowledge across departments and teams.
- Collaborated with DevOps contributing insights and assistance in configuring and optimizing the CI/CD pipeline.

- Brokermint
  - Led frontend engineers across multiple teams through integration of an external Real Estate Transaction Management System into CRM.
  - Collaborated with backend engineers on data schema.

#### Software Engineer - BoomTown - 05/2016 - 02/2022

Technology: React, Redux, .net

- Wrote React component library from scratch, tested with Jest, Cypress, testing-library.
- Implemented eslint and wrote custom rules, then refactored and reduced linter violations from 5,000+ to less than 500, in a 10 year old codebase
  - Used prettier to remove human error.
- Refactor legacy features to modern React, removing dozens of .net routes with client-side routing and React frontends.
- Participated in agile ceremonies, such as retrospectives, ticket pointing, and sprint planning, while incrementally releasing production code every 2 weeks to hundreds of thousands of users.

# 2014 — 2016 Frontend Developer, Erwin Penland

Greenville, SC

Technology: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular

- Developed pixel-perfect, cross-browser compatible websites and applications.
- Built dozens of campaign sites for companies like Verizon, Denny's, CIT Bank, as well as our own portfolio.
- Learned problem-solving skills, with the ability to address and resolve design-related challenges during the
  development process
- Accepted new role at BoomTown to work on a product, taking with me a ton of experience and expertise
  in building small to large web sites and applications while working in the digital agency space

2013 — 2014 Web Developer, Robojuice

Greenville, SC

 Engineered custom WordPress themes, templates, and widgets using a proprietary WordPress framework, showcasing both technical expertise and innovation in creating tailored web solutions with PHP, HTML, and CSS

LANGUAGES, FRAMEWORKS, SKILLS

JavaScript (React, Typescript,

Vue)

CSS (Sass, CSS Modules, Tailwind, Responsive Web

Design)

HTML (Accessible, Components, JSX)

UI Design, User Experience

Vite, Webpack

Backend: C#, .net, PHP, Laravel

Version Control: Git, Code

Reviews, Github

MySQL

Hosting Experience: Laravel

Forge, AWS

EDUCATION

Aug 2008 — May 2011 Mass Media, Anderson University

Anderson, SC

Apr 2013 — Jun 2013

Frontend Development, The Iron Yard Academy

Greenville, SC

LINKS

Personal Site

tyler.gs

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyler-sloan-16320755/

Github

https://github.com/tylersloan